This is not an easy question.
这不是一个容易的问题
So let's actually make a table with the values of these equations
那么让我们实际上做一个表格
on each of the four points.
用等式在这四个点上的值
Here we have the four points on the top row.
这里我们让四个点在这一行的最上面
And now, each of the other rows will be one of the functions.
现在 每一个其他行都是这些函数中的一个
Here's x + y.
这里是 x+y
We fill in the first row as follows, 0 plus 3 equals,
我们会像下面这样填第一行 0加3等于3
1 plus 2 equals 3, 2 plus 1 equals 3, and 3 plus 0 equals 3.
1加2等于3 2加1等于3 3加0等于3
So, we see that x + y, or
那么我们能够看到 x+y
the sum of the two coordinates is 3 for each one of the points.
或者是说这两个坐标的求和是3 对于每一个点而言
For the second row we see that the products are 0 times 3 equals 0 for
对于第二行 我们看到0乘3等于0
the first one.
这是第一个点的
1 times 2 equals 2 for the second.
1乘2等于2 这是第二个点的
2 times 1 equals 2 for the third, and 3 times 0 equals 0 for the fourth.
2乘1等于2这是第三个点的 3乘0等于0 这是第四个点的
And for the last one x squared we see that 0 squared equals 0,
对于最后一行 x 的平方 我们能够得到0的平方是0
1 squared equals 1, 2 squared equals 4, and 3 squared equals 9.
1的平方是1 2的平方是4 3的平方是9
So let's think, which of these equations separates the green and the red points.
那么让我们想想 这些等式中 哪一个能够分离绿色的点和红色的点
We look at the sum x + y and that gives us 3 at every value, so
我们看看求和  x + y 这个对于给每个点都给我们结果3
it doesn't really separates them.
所以它真的不能分离他们
If we look at x squared, so the first coordinates squared, we get 0 and 9 for
如果我看看 x 的平方 第一个坐标的平方 我们得到0和9
the red values and 1 and 4 for the green values.
对于红色的点 1和4对于绿色的点
This one also doesn't separate them since the red values are small and
这一个也不能分离他们 因为红色的点的值有小也有大
large 0 and 9 and the green values are in between 1 and 4.
0和9 绿色的值在1和4之中
So we look at the product xy and that gives us 0 for
所以我们看看这个乘积 xy 这个对于红色的点给我们0
the red values, and 2 for the green ones.
对于绿色的点给我们2
So, it seems that this one does a job, right?
那么这个似乎是可以完成任务的办法 对吗？
Since it’s a function that gives us one value for the red point and
因为这是一个函数 红色的点可以给我们一个值
another value from the green points then,
绿色的点又可以给我们另外一个值
it’s a function that can tell red and green apart.
这个函数能够区分开红色和绿色
So, if you said xy, that is correct.
那么如果你选 xy 那就是正确的
That is the magic equation we'll use.
那是一个我们将会使用的神奇的式子
So let's see, here we have our 4 points with coordinates x,y and
那么让我们看看 这里我们有4个点 坐标是 x y
a products of the coordinates xy.
还有一个坐标的乘积 xy
So for the, red points x, y, we have that the product xy = 0.
对于红色的点 x y 我们有乘积 xy=0
And for the green points, x, y, we have that the product xy = 2.
对于绿色的点 x y 我们有乘积 xy=2
And what separates a 0 and a 2?
什么能够分开0和2呢？
Well, a 1, so the equation xy = 1 will separate them.
那就是1 所以我们用式子 xy=1 就能够分开他们
And what is xy = 1?
那么 xy=1 是什么呢？
It's the same as y = 1/x, and the graph for
这个和 y = 1/x 是一样的
y = 1/x is precisely this hyperbola over here.
y = 1/x 的图准确来说 就是这里这个双曲线
That is the curve we wanted.
这就是我们想要的曲线
Okay, now let's look at what happens in three dimensions.
好的 现在让我们看看在三维空间中发生了什么
And we recall that our magic equation, which will separate the points is xy.
我们回忆一下能够分开点的神奇方程 xy
So we have our points with coordinates (0, 3), (1, 2), (2, 1), and (3, 0).
那么我们有坐标是 (0, 3) (1, 2) (2, 1) 和 (3, 0) 的点
And here we have a copy of the plane with an extra axis, the axis z, for
有着一个额外的轴 z 轴
height.
作为高度
So let's add this magic equation, xy, to our coordinate.
那么让我们加上这个神奇的等式 xy 到我们的坐标中
In other words, let's consider the map from two dimensions to three dimensions,
换句话说 让我们考虑一个两维到三维的映射
which takes the point in the plane with coordinates (x, y) to the point in space
这个把平面上坐标是  (x, y)  的点映射到了空间中
with coordinates( x, y, xy).
有着坐标 ( x, y, xy)
This map says the point (0, 3) to the point (0, 3, 0).
这个映射比如说把点 (0, 3) 映射到了 (0, 3, 0)
The point (1, 2) to the point (1, 2, 2).
把点 (1, 2) 映射到了 (1, 2, 2)
The point (2, 1) to the point (2, 1, 2).
把点 (2, 1) 映射到了 (2, 1, 2)
And the point (3, 0), to the point (3, 0, 0).
把点 (3, 0) 映射到了 (3, 0, 0)
So in a different way, it still separates the point since it sends
所以 以一个不同的方式 它仍然能够分离这些点 因为它把
the green points up by 2, and it leaves the red points underneath.
绿色的点升高到了2 把红色的点留在下面
Now what could separate these points?
现在什么能够分离这些点呢？
Well a plane could do it.
一个平面可以做这件事
This is the way to visualize the kernel trick in three dimensions.
这就是在三维空间中可视化核方法的一种方式